Put your hands together.
[Music]
We've come
to one of
the services that I always look forward
to this one because we are going to be
served
today through God's word by our
overseers, senior administrators, and
bishops. As we go through the seven
words that Jesus spoke on the
cross, each one has been allocated 3
minutes
maximum. So if you see them disappearing
here, it will be because they have gone
over 3 minutes and I've pressed a button
and they're going to disappear right
here.
We're going to have them
come in
pairs. The last words will only be one.
Between the pairs, the words that will
be spoken, we will have
hymns, worship songs, and different
things.
And so I'm going to ask you to welcome
every one of them before I call them up.
Please wait until I've named all of
them. We're going to have
[Applause]
Wait until I'm done. Let me tell you all
of them. Overseer Gasono, overseer Samu,
overseers Lamini, Bishop Moresi, Senior
Administrator Preacher Dingmani, Senior
Administrator Vincent Mukansi, Bishop
Ezekiel M. Can we give them all a big
hand? Baselon, please.
They will be coming in
pairs one after the other with music in
between. So I will not come back over
here until the last words or the last
person who will be giving us the seventh
words. It's always a pleasure Barcelona.
These leaders who will be speaking here
these are leaders who lead with me. We
call them leadership because we meet in
a meeting where we make major decisions
but they're also part of uh the regional
heads. They are heading up our different
churches, the different uh regions that
we are leading. These are people who
serve with us. So, and also Reinma
Bishop who of
course whom we are very grateful that
she's also here. And so to kick start
everything Barcelona with the words,
"Father, I forgive them for they don't
know what to do." After that, truly I
say to you today, you will be with me in
paradise. The next song after that,
Jesus said to his mother,"Woman, this is
your son." And he said to his disciples,
this is your mother. And then my God, my
God, why you have forsaken me? And then
another song, then I thirst, it is
finished. Another song, Father, into
your hands I commend my spirit. And then
we are concluding to kickstart us today.
Kim Bishop overseer Gono. Can you give a
powerful warm welcome? She will be
followed by overseers Sam Masu and then
overseers Lamini, Bishop Muresi, senior
administrator preacher Tongmani, senior
administrator V Mukansi and finally
Bishop Mat. Give my bishop a big hand as
she comes and three minutes starts
now. Amen. Greetings in the wonderful
name of our Lord and Savior Jesus
Christ. Amen. I'm doing the last words
three minutes please.
It's
done. Okay. The last prayer that Jesus
Christ prayed before the crucifixion to
the father. And then is the first of the
seven last words. He
says, "Father, forgive them for they do
not know what they
do." This word, it reminds you that he
was calling a father, not just God,
because God is father to him. He's God
the father, God the son, and God the
holy spirit. You remember the father of
the prodical son who was able to forgive
the son even though he has gone his
wayward ways but we know that fathers
are the ones who forgive. So we realize
first of all prayer is important. Jesus
Christ prayed the importance of
forgiveness talking to God and father
directly.
There is a purpose involved in how Jesus
chose his last waste on the cross. The
purpose for the word in Luke chapter 19
verse
10. For the son of man is come to seek
and save which was lost. That was the
purpose. Jesus is executed with
criminals. The worst of his creature
side by side with condemned criminals.
Can you imagine Jesus the one who didn't
commit any sin crucified with those who
committed crimes? That's the picture
that you see on
Calvary. And he is
executed at hands of those he loved. The
people who were executing Jesus Christ
is the very people that he loved. the
very people that he was made
[Applause]
that that they were made in his
image. Amen. So you realize that the two
criminals represents us if we rebel
against God will start criminal
acts. So Jesus negotiates our salvation
with the
father. Salvation is forever close and
available. It is God's top priority to
men. In Psalm
85:9, he says, "Surely his salvation is
nigh to them that fear him, that glory
may dwell in the land." Baswani, if you
fear God, there'll be glory in the land.
Now, let's understand what happened at
the cross. His blood became a fountain.
The dilemma of our sin frustration had
surrounded him in qualbaring at as a
reality of both h sides of crucified the
criminals that were crucified with Jesus
Christ. So when he shed his blood it was
a fountain where will be I like it it's
called a fountain. It is not just
something it means it flows forever. It
never dries.
Now in Luke
23:4, then Jesus said, "Father, forgive
them for they do not know what they do."
In John
12:27-28, Jesus prays, "Now is my soul
troubled, and what shall I say? Father,
save me from this hour, but this purpose
I came to this hour. Father glorify your
name. I mean Jesus Christ was pre
predicting his crucifixion and he's
saying father when that moment comes can
you save me but because he understood
purpose it was necessary for him to go
to the
cross with the father's forgiveness
comes first. It is the father who knows
best what to do about our forgiveness.
That is his story. The word is prayer. A
prayer for forgiveness for what? Man's
rebelliousness
nature. People could not understand the
moment. They knew Jesus had such power
that Jesus could do anything. But here
we hear people were mocking Jesus. They
were saying everything that is negative.
Little did they know why Jesus had to
die. They never had a revelation for
that. And we realize that Jesus Christ
died because he came to save them. Now
there's something that I want us to
understand. As he was in on the cross,
he was in a position where he was
lifted. Jesus could look down to see the
perpetrators and could could see look up
to see the demands of the righteousness.
He was between men and God. And he
prayed, "Father, forgive them." And from
this position, Jesus acts as a public
defender, presenting his case to the
righteous judge. From the cross, it was
a strategic advantage. He pleased the
father. Father, forgive them for they
don't know what to what they're doing.
And I pray that may God help us to
understand when we live a life that does
not acknowledge God as Jehovah, it's the
ignorance of men. But Jesus Christ
pleaded with God to say, "Yes, they are
guilty. They've moved away from you, but
I plead the case as if they ignorance."
Don't forget Jesus understood how to be
an advocate for us. And thus the power
of the cross, forgive them for they do
not know what to do. May God bless you
for the reading of his word. Thank you.
Hallelujah.
The second words of our Lord Jesus
Christ on the
cross. Truly I say to you today, you
will be with me in paradise. The second
word of our Lord Jesus Christ on the
cross is recorded in Luke 23:42 to verse
43. The Bible says, "Then one of the
thieves said, Jesus, remember me when
you come into your kingdom." Jesus
answered him, "Truly I tell you, today
you will be with me in paradise." In the
message translation, it says, he said,
"Don't worry." Which is the character of
God being consistent for us not to
worry. Don't worry, I will today.
Rather, don't worry. I will today you
will join me in paradise. The Living
Bible says, and Jesus replied, "Today
you will be with me in paradise, this is
a solemn promise. All the thief asked
was to be remembered." But our savior
Lord Jesus did much more than he had
ever requested. This response of our
Lord Christ Jesus was an earnest promise
of immediate salvation and companion in
paradise to the one who was repenting.
The second word of Jesus Christ can be
outlined in few words that are very
important. Number one, it is the genuine
request from the thief. The thief who
knew that he can cry to Christ and
Christ can have his bag. The second word
that reminds us of the promise by our
Lord Jesus Christ. Jesus who doesn't
judge. Jesus who wants to offer you
forgiveness. The third word reminds us
of a promise in of paradise. The word
paradise in its context talks about a
place of rest, a place of peace, a place
of joy. Hebrews 10:23 says, "Let us hold
fast to the confession of our hope
without wavering. For he who has
promised is faithful." This scripture
reminds us number four that Christ
wanted to leave us with a message of
hope. This hope was God's response to a
human being's suffering. When we use the
word hope as an acronym, we say we are
holding on to the promises that are
eternal. And finally, this word father
that we read about speaks of our call to
repentance. This thief at the nick of
time, just before his life was taken,
remembered that there's a Christ in
heaven. Romans 10:11 says as the
scripture says for whoever believes in
him will never be put to shame. Romans
10:13 says for whenever whoever calls on
the name of the Lord whoever calls on
the name of the Lord will be saved.
Jesus answered and said to him truly I
tell you today you will be with me in
paradise. Amen.
[Applause]
[Music]
stones
are
[Music]
all shall keep him.
of
falling as
[Music]
voice. Oh
mighty one.
[Music]
[Applause]
All
[Music]
sing on his face.
worship
[Music]
when
shrinking
[Applause]
when it sink.
[Music]
Oh my god.
[Applause]
[Music]
When
[Applause]
sessresses
through
the wall
And
when I lost it,
to
[Applause]
[Music]
So
hallelujah. Hallelujah.
The third word, John chapter 19 from
verse 26. When Jesus therefore saw his
mother and the disciple whom he loved
standing by, he said to his
mother,"Woman, behold your son." Then he
said to the disciple, "Behold your
mother." And from that hour, that
disciple took her in his home. As his
life was ebbing away in the deep agony
and pain at the foot of the cross was
Jesus's mother and the disciple whom he
loved. This was a moment that all who
had known him had deserted him. The
Bible only mentions a handful of people
that were at the cross when Jesus was
crucified. When he saw his mother at the
foot of the cross, he just saw it it saw
beyond just appearance and saw her pain
and saw an unspeakable grief and
anxiety. This was a moment for Mary when
the words of Simeon rang true as we
observe in the book of Luke
2:34-35. Then Simon blessed them and
said to Mary his mother, "Behold, this
child is destined for the fall and the
rising of many in Israel. for a son
which will be spoken against. Yes, a
sword will pierce through your own soul
that the thoughts of many hearts may be
revealed. This was a sword piercing
through her soul. It's quite remarkable
that Mary in the midst of such anguish
remains faithful to the call of being a
mother and she stands hard and firm
while her son is hanging on the cross.
You can imagine the agony of a mother
looking at the cross where the sun was
hanging. A sword was indeed piercing
through her soul. Aw pink would write
and say her life was lived in the
background among shadows. But now when
the supreme hour strikes of her son's
agony, when the world casts out the
child of her womb, she stands there at
the cross nearest to the cruel tree
bound by the love for her dying son.
Looking down in the midst of mortal
agony and pain, Christ shows his
humanity and passion. This was a
demonstration of true love in the midst
of pain and pending death. While Jesus
was going through this agony, he shows
concern for his earthly mother and he
entrusted her to the care of the woman
whom he loved. This was to fulfill the
fifth commandment. He recognized he
still had the obligation to make sure
that his mother was taken care of. You
see, you have to understand that in the
midst of everything happening at the
cross, there is love at the cross. Jesus
reminds us at the cross that no matter
the agony, the pain, love still descends
from the cross and that our families
matter. Much as he died for us that we
could be reconciled to God, he also
established us as a godly family. We are
a family because Jesus recognized it
right at the cross. The sin that we have
experienced reminds us again the part
the price that was paid for us to be
adopted. By the virtue of this
statement, Jesus seals our adoption into
the family of God. And from that very
hour, our adoption was sealed. Just as
John took his mother, shall I dare say
adopted his mother. We too are now
adopted and can be adopted into the
family of God. From this very act, we as
believers are sanctified to be adopted
into the family of God. From that
moment, you and I are bonded as brothers
and sisters. As Paul would write in
Ephesians chapter 1:5, having
predestined us to the adoption as sons
by Christ Jesus to himself, according to
his good pleasure of his will, to the
praise of the glory of his grace by
which he have made us acceptable in the
beloved. Because of the cross, you are
never alone. Because of the cross, you
have been made into the family of God.
Bless God bless you.
Amen. Hallelujah.
We are now going into the fourth
word. And Jesus was hanging on the
cross. It was not It was 3:00 in the
afternoon and he's been hanging there
for 3
hours and he broke the
silence by crying, "My God, my God, why
have you forsaken me?"
The scripture reading comes from Matthew
27:46 and it says, "And about the 9th
hour Jesus cried out with a loud voice
saying
[Applause]
Eliasakani." That is my God, my God, why
have you forsaken me? Brothers and
sisters, at this moment Jesus was
bearing the sins of the world.
He was carrying your sins and he was
carrying my sins because the Bible tells
us in Isaiah
53:6 it said the Lord had laid on him
the iniquity of us all. He was dying as
a substitute. He was taking my place and
to him was imputed the guilt of our
sins. God was punishing Jesus as if he
had personally committed every wicked
deed. And yet the Bible tells us that
Jesus carried our sins. When we read
first Peter
22:24, it says he personally carried our
sins in his body on the cross so that we
can be dead to sin and live for what is
right. By his wounds, you are healed.
No, what was happening when Jesus was
saying, "My God, my God, why hast thou
forsaken you?" Jesus cried out because
he was expressing his feelings of
abandonment as God placed the sins of
the world on him. This was because Jesus
had been made sin. And we know that
Habacook 1:E3 it says that God is too
pure to behold the sin or iniquity.
Jesus continued to say, "My God, my God,
why have you forsaken me?" It was the
manifestation of God's hatred of sin
because Jesus experienced in that
terrible hour. Brothers and sisters,
Jesus was forsaken by God in this world
because became very dark on that lone
hill. So that in our darkest hour, God
will always be with you and God will
say, "I will never leave you nor forsake
you." God will never forsake you because
his son was forsaken in our place and
Jesus was forsaken that you may never be
forsaken. But in this hour there is hope
as the sin of man was upon the Lord
Jesus. The Bible tells us in 2
Corinthians 5:21, he made the one who
did not no sin to be sin for us so that
in him we might become the righteousness
of God. Jesus enjoyed the separation
that you and I deserve. In turn, you and
I receive the righteousness of Christ.
And because Jesus was literally forsaken
by God the father that day we have hope
and confidence that he will never leave
us because Jesus instead of being
abandoned or held at arms length were
invited to press in and come into the
presence of God. Therefore Jesus
suffering at the cross showed us how
much God loves you. It shows you the
great love of God the father who sent
his son to suffer and die in your place.
And when Jesus said, "My God, my God,
why have you forsaken me?" He was
thinking of each and every one of you.
God bless you.
[Music]
Amen.
Hello.
[Music]
Hello. Hello.
Hello.
Jesus.
Hello. Awesome.
Oh,
I
receive
my Oh,
Fire
City
Jesus.
Heat. Heat.
But
my hallelujah.
Hallelujah. I
thirst. John 19:28.
Jesus knew that his mission was now
finished. And to fulfill scripture, he
said, "I am
thirsty." This word seems to be or seem
not to fit from all the other words that
you've heard and you are still going to
have to hear. All the other words, they
seem to make him heroic. They seem to
make him almost mythical in his response
to what he's dealing
with. When we get to this fifth
word, he is not viewed as heroic but as
human. And maybe that is what we need.
Maybe we need to
know that it is okay to have human
moments when we are dealing with
seemingly unethical uh
challenges. Jesus speak the word I
thirst from the cross. It seems to
reveal his interconnectedness.
Jesus, this word that he speaks is not
necessarily an original word, but it can
be traced throughout the Old
Testament. We see this in Psalm
22:15 and Psalm 69:21.
Jesus almost says to
us that he he he he he he basically
comes from as much as he is God but you
can trace his origin uh from the Old
Testament. His roots are in in the Old
Testament.
What this is saying to us is that
whenever God uses us, we must know and
respect where we come
from. The other word that we learn from
this is
integrity. The integrity of
Christ. For the first time, Christ
expresses his personal desires.
Even when he is faced with death, he
still puts uh the desires of others over
his
own. All the other words, like we've
said, they are about other
people. But this one is about him. He is
teaching us that we can still love and
care for others even when we are going
through challenges ourselves.
Sometimes God causes us to go through
things so that we can be a blessing to
others. We should not be selfcentered
and consumed with self and forget the
bigger purpose for our lives.
Even in the midst of pain, in the midst
of difficulty and chaos that Jesus was
experiencing at the
cross, he is saying to us his father was
behind him. He was there helping him.
And even in your own chaos, in your own
desires, in your own anxieties, we need
to know that the father is there. And
the father is working a plan to get out
to get get us out of the challenges that
we are facing. I thirst. God bless
[Applause]
you. Hallelujah. Orlando
Stadium. It is
finished. John 19:30.
When he received the drink, Jesus said,
"It is finished." With that, he bowed
his head and gave up his
spirit. What is
finished? The plan of God is finished.
God's plan for the salvation and the
restoration of all mankind is finished.
Where was it finished? It was at Golgota
on a cruel Roman cross as it was
prophesied. It was finished at Calvary.
How was it finished? Jesus gave himself
to be arrested, to be tried, to be
executed between two criminals, and yet
he had no
sin. When was it finished? In the
fullness of time. Because Jesus once
said, "No one can take my life away from
me, but I lay down of myself." Jesus
gave away his life to finish the work he
came to
do. Who finished it? Jesus, the great I
am, the lamb of God, the last Adam, the
Messiah, God the Son.
Why did Jesus finish it? No one else
could finish it but Jesus Christ. He is
the alpha and omega, the beginning and
the end. No one could be found worthy.
The Bible tells us in Revelations 5
verse 3 and 5. The Bible says, "No one
in heaven or on earth or under the earth
could open the scroll but Jesus, the
lion of the tribe of Judah, the root of
David has conquered." The plan of
salvation began in heaven, lived out on
earth, and was finished on the cross by
the one who started it. Jesus Christ
paid the full price of our sins. And on
the cross he said, "It is finished."
Again I ask, why did Jesus say, "It is
finished?" To demonstrate his love for
us all. He died for all our sins so that
our salvation may be complete. He said,
"It is finished.
Drawing.
You f
delay
mighty
[Music]
tr I
Imaturity. I feel
He
[Music]
was Heat. Heat.
Heat. Heat.
Heat. Heat. Heat.
Heat. Yeah.
Heat. Heat. Heat. Heat.
Your
chance
might be
[Applause]
Hallelujah.
Hallelujah. According to Luke's gospel
chapter
23:46 the last words of Christ on the
cross when he was embracing our sal
death death for our salvation this is
what he said and when Jesus had cried
out with a loud voice he said
father into your
hands I commit my
spirit having said this, he breathd his
lust. Christ was facing the reality of
death, a separation of his body from his
spirit and his spirit from God. And he's
praying and trusting his spirit in the
hands of God that God may keep it safe.
God may keep it safe because our spirit
are secure in God's hands. The devil
won't trouble them and satanic powers
won't capture them. The hands of God
represents his power, his care, his
protection and his work on our behalf.
So Jesus rested peacefully in death
after placing his spirit in God's safe
hands. He did not know. He did not fear
death knowing that he's assured that his
spirit is in tender hands of a faithful
father and a saving father. He rested in
comfort. As Grace Folk says, we are in
good hands when we are in God's hands.
So God's caring fatherhood for us as his
children does not end with our earthly
life but continues forever beyond the
grave. The psalmist in Psalm 103 verse
13 says as a father has compassion on
his children. The Lord has compassion on
those who fear him. Let me close in John
10:29. Jesus says, "My father who has
given them to me is greater than them
all. No one can snatch them out of the
father's hands." When we are in the
father's hands, we are eternally
secured. eternally secured. Nothing can
separate us from the love of God. When
we are in his hands, and nothing can
shake those who are secure in God's
hands. May the Lord bless
[Applause]
you. Why don't you join hands with your
neighbor? We thank you, Lord, that
nothing will separate us from your
love. We thank you that as you hung on
the cross and died,
You did it all for
us and thousands of years
later we can stand and
remember what you did for us.
Thank you for being so
gracious to allow
us the privilege of being
here. And even today as we
have listened to your
word, as we've worshiped, as as we've
praised, we thank you for your
grace. Thank you for reminding us not to
forget that you died to buy our
soul. You died to heal our
bodies. You died to deliver us from
powers of
darkness. You hung on the cross and gave
your life for us. And so today, we want
to thank
you as we hold hands
today. We pray for one another. Will you
begin to pray for your neighbor,
please? Thank you, Lord
Jesus. Lord, I pray for my brother. I
pray for my
sister. I pray that your grace will rest
upon
them. I pray that your spirit will rest
upon them. I thank you for who you
are. I thank you for your
blessing. We give you honor and praise.
Just before we conclude
everything, we have Andy Lea Majola, a
singer from
Devon known for his gospel hits, his
songwriting where he connects with
people globally by reflecting everyday
life
experiences. He was born in Emma
Cambelli village in
Kesn. He faced a difficult childhood
after being abandoned by his parents.
But thankfully raised by his
grandmother. Despite the
hardships, he built a successful life
and now he is married to Ungo
Majola with whom they both have two
daughters and a son. With over 15 years
in the music industry, Andel has won
several
awards, including eight Crown Gospel
Awards.
He's also the founder of Debban's All
Nations Cathedral International
Church. Though his exact age is
unknown, he appears to be in his mid
years.
And so today as we close out, Andel is
going to come and let's join together in
worship and put our hands together for
Hallelujah.
Hallelujah. Hallelujah.
[Music]
[Applause]
The
bishop lady
bishop. Amen.
Amen. Amen.
[Music]
[Applause]
Guuling to me.
I'll grab
[Music]
you
[Applause]
[Music]
father to be
Oh, that's amazing.
[Music]
Don't stop.
[Applause]
[Music]
is
[Applause]
[Music]
I was
Oh, you don't want to
[Music]
[Applause]
hear I
[Music]
Jesus stage is a
sugateful bishop to be here today. I'm
just a son in the house of
God. 26 years in the music industry.
We've written about 350 songs that you
have sung in in a church any given
Sunday.
[Music]
We we we wrote those
songs. We wrote the
[Music]
song.
Hallelujah. Now we The Lord has spoken
to me after 26 years in the industry
that before us
The Lord has
said, "For the very first time in our
land, we have a new book of songs.
[Music]
this
without the vessel that God has blessed
us with a South
Africa. South Africa, you are blessed to
have Bishop Mus.
[Music]
Hallelujah.
No. Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Praise
[Music]
Godish. So we could not complete this
without asking the bishop to pen a
forward for this book. Now your father,
your bishop has written a four word of
the book.
[Music]
[Applause]
It is my honor and privilege to present
the bishop the first copy of this
book.
Listen, history will record this day.
18 April 20258.
809 South
Africa Stadium.
[Music]
Hallelujah. Bishop.
Bishop, you are a blessing in our
nation. This is a humble man.
South
Africa.
Hallelujah. Hallelujah.
[Music]
All
right. Thank you so
much. I think this book the
written is because I don't know if you
know I've always
said why are we not composing songs and
writing them and compiling them?
Becauseam for every move of
God there are special songs that the
Holy Spirit brings for that generation
you know and at least taste you've been
singing these songs you didn't know
there's also su
songs we need more books like
this for being a pioneer of pioneering
this because some of us we've talked
about these things for about 30 years 40
years talking about it and I was blessed
mama about this
project to have the privilege to write
the forward this book is available get
it
sing these
hymns pass them on to the next
generation do you want to sing one more
before before sayaba just one
Oh, only we leave copies for the church
and the bishop will tell you how to get
them. The only one to train a
[Music]
copy Africa, this is your song.
Hallelujah.
D where my son
[Music]
Hey.
Hey
[Applause]
[Music]
my
hallelujah. Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat. Heat.
[Applause]
What's up?
[Music]
I
ass
it's all
[Music]
it's on my side.
side. Bye-bye.
[Music]
[Applause]
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
Somebody's a I'm a I'm a
I'm a
[Music]
I love
you. I love you.
[Music]
was a
salon. I'm a salon.
Ius
[Music]
What's the one?
Who
is
Hallelujah?
Hallelujah. Wow. What a way to close us
out. Just few announcements. Remain
standing.